The Universal Declaration of Human Rights is a milestone document in the history of human rights.
Drafted by representatives with different legal and cultural backgrounds from all regions of the world,
the declaration was proclaimed by the United Nations General Assembly in Paris on ten December nineteen forty eight.
It sets out for the first time fundamental human rights to be universally protected.
All human beings are born free and equal in dignity and rights.
They are endowed with reason and conscience and should act towards one another in a spirit of brotherhood.
Everyone has the right to life, liberty and security of person.
No one shall be held in slavery or servitude.
Everyone has the right to freedom of thought, conscience and religion.
Everyone has the right to freedom of opinion and expression.